Marc Franco Salvador

Valencia, 46014, Valencian Community, Spain

E-mail: <u>marc.franco@symanto.net</u> – LinkedIn: <u>es.linkedin.com/in/marfrasa/en</u>
CV (extended version) in PDF

Summary

I'm a Principal Research Scientist at Symanto, a data analytics company based on psycholinguistic profiling. In this role, I work with my team to provide our data analysis platform with novel solutions based on the latest techniques of natural language processing, machine and deep learning.

I have more than five years of experience as a researcher in projects related to multilingual natural language processing and information retrieval. Those projects allowed me to acquire a strong background in machine learning, data science, analytics, and mining.

I'm a truly passionate, focused, and creative researcher. I like to read blogs and scientific papers about computational linguistics, data mining, and deep learning to keep up with the latest advances. While I enjoy all aspects of my job, I think my favorite stage of a project is defining the main data pipeline to solve a concrete objective. I also find very stimulating the part of the result analysis and pipeline tuning.

I obtained my PhD in computer science in the Universitat Politècnica de València (Spain) with cum laude distinction, where I also obtained my Engineer's Degree in Computer Science and my Master's Degree in Artificial Intelligence, Pattern Recognition and Digital Image. In the course of my career I have published near 25 scientific articles, some of them in top conferences, and participated in several research internships around the world.

Professional experience

Principal Research Scientist

May 2018 - Today

Symanto

- Person in charge of the research staff
- Decision making on new lines of research and their implementation
- Supervision and participation in the development of the new artificial intelligence-based solutions

Innovation Lead

Apr 2017 - Apr 2018

Symanto Group

- Lead a team of data scientists and psycholinguists
- Provide the data analysis platform with novel solutions based on the latest techniques of natural language processing and deep learning

Data Scientist

Dec 2016 - Apr 2017

Symanto Group

- Research on cross-lingual and cross-domain deep learning solutions
- Application of data science techniques to text analytics

Research Fellow

Sep 2016 - Nov 2016

Data and Web Science Group, Universität Mannheim

Research on several natural language processing projects

Symanto Group

- Research on cross-lingual deep learning solutions
- Application of data science techniques to text analytics

Senior Technician - NLP researcher

Jul 2014 - May 2016

PRHLT Research Center, Universitat Politècnica de València

- SOMEMBED research project, funded by the Spanish Ministry of Economy and Competitiveness
- DIANA-APPLICATIONS research project, funded by the Spanish Ministry of Economy and Competitiveness

Technical Specialist - NLP researcher

Apr 2014 – Jun 2014

Italica Research Group, University of Seville

DOCGU research project, funded by the Spanish Ministry of Economy and Competitiveness

Research Fellow

Apr 2013 - Mar 2014

Linguistic Computing Laboratory, Sapienza University of Rome

MultiJEDI research project, funded by the 5-year ERC Starting Grant No. 259234

Senior Technician - NLP researcher

Aug 2012 - Dec 2012

NLE Lab, Universitat Politècnica de València

TEXT-ENTERPRISE 2.0 research project, funded by the Spanish Ministry of Education and Science

Education

PhD in Natural Language Processing and Information Retrieval

Mar 2013 - May 2017

Universitat Politècnica de València, Valencia, Spain

- Title: A Cross-domain and Cross-language Knowledge-based Representation of Text and its Meaning
- Score: Cum laude

MSc in Artificial Intelligence, Pattern Recognition and Digital Image

Sep 2011 - Feb 2013

<u>Universitat Politècnica de València</u>, Valencia, Spain

- Title: Cross-Language Plagiarism Detection using a Multilingual Semantic Network
- Final score: Cum laude

BSc in Computer Science Engineering (5-year degree)

Sep 2006 - Sep 2011

<u>Universitat Politècnica de València</u>, Valencia, Spain

Specialization in Artificial Intelligence and Languages

Publications

Available on Google Scholar: goo.gl/srdC6D

References

Available upon request.